<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">

  <channel>
    <title>REWIRED: THE IBOGAINE EXPERIENCE</title>
    <link>https://theibogainstitute.org</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <description>Rewired: The Ibogaine Experience shares real stories from patients and families who have experienced ibogaine therapy for PTSD, addiction, Parkinson's disease, and other conditions.
    
Brought to you by IBOGA Wellness Institute.
    
Every week, you'll hear honest conversations about struggle, recovery, and what happens after treatment. Veterans with PTSD, people overcoming addiction, patients with Parkinson's experiencing symptom improvements, and the family members who supported them through the decision.
    
These are authentic stories backed by research. No false promises. No wellness industry marketing. Just real people sharing what worked when traditional treatments failed.
    
If you're researching options for someone you love, or seeking answers for yourself, you're not alone.
    
New episodes every week. Real stories. Real outcomes. Real hope.</description>

    <!-- Set this to the final public URL where THIS RSS XML is hosted -->
    <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aidatamanagement/Iboga_Podcast/main/Rewired.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

    <!-- Recommended metadata -->
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:15:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>

    <!-- Spotify reads iTunes podcast tags -->
    <itunes:author>Sarah Mitchell</itunes:author>
    <itunes:summary>Sarah Mitchell has personal experience researching treatments for a loved one at 2am. She knows what it's like to be exhausted, hopeful, and trying to separate science from marketing. After seeing the real results ibogaine offers, Sarah brings you the research and shares authentic experiences from people who have walked this path.
Sarah speaks to you as a peer, not an expert. She's been where you are.</itunes:summary>
    <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>

    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:name>Shubakar Poda</itunes:name>
      <itunes:email>contactus@theibogainstitute.org</itunes:email>
    </itunes:owner>

    <itunes:category text="Technology"/>

    <!-- Prefer hosting your own cover art long-term, but this URL is syntactically fine -->
    <itunes:image href="https://oimqzyfmglyhljjuboek.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/IBoga_Podcast_Files/Rewired%20v3.jpg"/>

    <!-- Optional nice-to-haves -->
    <itunes:subtitle>Supabase-hosted podcast feed test</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:keywords>supabase, podcast, testing, aidm</itunes:keywords>



  
 
    

  
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The GDNF Connection: How Ibogaine Triggers Brain Repair in Parkinson's Disease]]></title>
      <itunes:image href="https://oimqzyfmglyhljjuboek.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/IBoga_Podcast_Files/TheGDNFConnectionHowIbogaineTriggersBrainRepairinParkinsonsDisease_Episode_Image.jpeg" />
      <description><![CDATA[Research indicates that a specific dose of ibogaine can increase GDNF, a critical brain repair protein, by up to twelve-fold in the Ventral Tegmental Area and six-fold in the Substantia Nigra—the very regions ravaged by Parkinson's disease. These findings are foundational to the profound changes our clients experience.

This scientific discovery translates into genuine hope and significant improvements for millions. Just like Michael, a 62-year-old former engineer who battled Parkinson's for a decade, facing increasing tremors and stiffness that stole his independence, clients are discovering a path forward. He came to us after conventional treatments offered little more than symptom management, desperate for an alternative.

Parkinson's affects over a million people in the U.S. alone, a number projected to increase by 60% in the next two decades. It's the second most common neurodegenerative disease after Alzheimer's. For too long, the conventional wisdom has been that Parkinson's is irreversible, a progressive decline that can only be managed, not halted or reversed. Standard treatments like Levodopa offer temporary relief, but often come with debilitating side effects and diminish in efficacy over time, leaving clients and their families desperate for something more.

The core problem in Parkinson's is the loss of dopamine-producing neurons. This is where the GDNF connection becomes so pivotal. GDNF stands for Glial Cell Line-Derived Neurotrophic Factor, and it's a naturally occurring protein that acts like a guardian and restorer for these vital dopamine neurons. It helps them survive, thrive, and even regenerate. Previous attempts to deliver GDNF directly to the brain were invasive and inconsistent, using gene therapy or direct brain infusions that often failed to provide consistent, widespread benefit.

The breakthrough is that ibogaine naturally stimulates the brain's own GDNF production. Studies show that a specific dosage of ibogaine leads to a twelve-fold increase of GDNF in the Ventral Tegmental Area and a six-fold increase in the Substantia Nigra. These are precisely the brain regions where dopamine neurons degenerate in Parkinson's. This means ibogaine offers a non-invasive way to boost the brain's inherent protective and restorative mechanisms, directly addressing the underlying neurological damage, not just masking symptoms. Ibogaine crosses the blood-brain barrier and activates cellular pathways that upregulate GDNF expression, essentially telling the brain to start repairing itself.

The clinical evidence is building. Ambio Life Sciences launched one of the world's first clinical ibogaine neuroregenerative programs, treating clients with conditions like Parkinson's, MS, and essential tremor. One specific retreat program with thirty Parkinson's clients reported an average of 70% reduction in Parkinson's severity by the end of their fourteen-day program. What's truly remarkable is the rapid response; many clients experienced a 50% or more symptom reduction within just three to four days. Our client Michael experienced this firsthand. His tremors, which had made daily tasks almost impossible, significantly subsided, and his mobility improved noticeably within the first week of his treatment. Beyond motor symptoms like tremor and rigidity, clients report improvements in non-motor symptoms such as eyesight, neuropathic pain, sleep quality, anxiety, and mood. The sustained benefit comes, in part, from noribogaine, a metabolite of ibogaine that remains active in the body for months, continuing to provide therapeutic effects and neuroplasticity.

Ibogaine's effectiveness where single-mechanism drugs often fail stems from its multi-system approach. First, it directly modulates the dopamine system, addressing the core deficit in Parkinson's. Second, it has powerful neuroprotective properties, potentially slowing or even reversing disease progression. Third, it enhances neuroplasticity, helping the brain form new, healthy pathways. And fourth, it offers anti-inflammatory effects, reducing neuroinflammation which is increasingly understood to play a role in Parkinson's.

For clients with Parkinson's, the treatment protocol is carefully optimized to account for physical challenges. This can involve a specific loading dose of ibogaine, followed by microdosing for maintenance, which uses very small amounts of the substance to sustain benefits with minimal psychoactive effects. Throughout this, safety is paramount. We adhere to rigorous medical supervision and protocols, including 24/7 medical monitoring, comprehensive cardiac surveillance, and co-administration of magnesium for heart protection. This meticulous approach ensures that a powerful compound is delivered as breakthrough medicine.

For clients like Michael, this means hope where hope was once lost. While we are not claiming a cure, we are seeing measurable, significant improvements in what was previously considered an irreversible condition. This shift from managing decline to supporting regeneration is profound. Ongoing research at institutions like Dalhousie University, alongside pharmaceutical development of compounds like CKBR-12, continues to validate ibogaine's potential. Provisional patents are even being filed for methods that provide rapid symptom reduction in neurodegenerative disorders. For millions affected by Parkinson's, ibogaine offers not just symptom management, but genuine hope for a better quality of life.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[Research indicates that a specific dose of ibogaine can increase GDNF, a critical brain repair protein, by up to twelve-fold in the Ventral Tegmental Area and six-fold in the Substantia Nigra—the very regions ravaged by Parkinson's disease. These findings are foundational to the profound changes our clients experience.

This scientific discovery translates into genuine hope and significant improvements for millions. Just like Michael, a 62-year-old former engineer who battled Parkinson's for a decade, facing increasing tremors and stiffness that stole his independence, clients are discovering a path forward. He came to us after conventional treatments offered little more than symptom management, desperate for an alternative.

Parkinson's affects over a million people in the U.S. alone, a number projected to increase by 60% in the next two decades. It's the second most common neurodegenerative disease after Alzheimer's. For too long, the conventional wisdom has been that Parkinson's is irreversible, a progressive decline that can only be managed, not halted or reversed. Standard treatments like Levodopa offer temporary relief, but often come with debilitating side effects and diminish in efficacy over time, leaving clients and their families desperate for something more.

The core problem in Parkinson's is the loss of dopamine-producing neurons. This is where the GDNF connection becomes so pivotal. GDNF stands for Glial Cell Line-Derived Neurotrophic Factor, and it's a naturally occurring protein that acts like a guardian and restorer for these vital dopamine neurons. It helps them survive, thrive, and even regenerate. Previous attempts to deliver GDNF directly to the brain were invasive and inconsistent, using gene therapy or direct brain infusions that often failed to provide consistent, widespread benefit.

The breakthrough is that ibogaine naturally stimulates the brain's own GDNF production. Studies show that a specific dosage of ibogaine leads to a twelve-fold increase of GDNF in the Ventral Tegmental Area and a six-fold increase in the Substantia Nigra. These are precisely the brain regions where dopamine neurons degenerate in Parkinson's. This means ibogaine offers a non-invasive way to boost the brain's inherent protective and restorative mechanisms, directly addressing the underlying neurological damage, not just masking symptoms. Ibogaine crosses the blood-brain barrier and activates cellular pathways that upregulate GDNF expression, essentially telling the brain to start repairing itself.

The clinical evidence is building. Ambio Life Sciences launched one of the world's first clinical ibogaine neuroregenerative programs, treating clients with conditions like Parkinson's, MS, and essential tremor. One specific retreat program with thirty Parkinson's clients reported an average of 70% reduction in Parkinson's severity by the end of their fourteen-day program. What's truly remarkable is the rapid response; many clients experienced a 50% or more symptom reduction within just three to four days. Our client Michael experienced this firsthand. His tremors, which had made daily tasks almost impossible, significantly subsided, and his mobility improved noticeably within the first week of his treatment. Beyond motor symptoms like tremor and rigidity, clients report improvements in non-motor symptoms such as eyesight, neuropathic pain, sleep quality, anxiety, and mood. The sustained benefit comes, in part, from noribogaine, a metabolite of ibogaine that remains active in the body for months, continuing to provide therapeutic effects and neuroplasticity.

Ibogaine's effectiveness where single-mechanism drugs often fail stems from its multi-system approach. First, it directly modulates the dopamine system, addressing the core deficit in Parkinson's. Second, it has powerful neuroprotective properties, potentially slowing or even reversing disease progression. Third, it enhances neuroplasticity, helping the brain form new, healthy pathways. And fourth, it offers anti-inflammatory effects, reducing neuroinflammation which is increasingly understood to play a role in Parkinson's.

For clients with Parkinson's, the treatment protocol is carefully optimized to account for physical challenges. This can involve a specific loading dose of ibogaine, followed by microdosing for maintenance, which uses very small amounts of the substance to sustain benefits with minimal psychoactive effects. Throughout this, safety is paramount. We adhere to rigorous medical supervision and protocols, including 24/7 medical monitoring, comprehensive cardiac surveillance, and co-administration of magnesium for heart protection. This meticulous approach ensures that a powerful compound is delivered as breakthrough medicine.

For clients like Michael, this means hope where hope was once lost. While we are not claiming a cure, we are seeing measurable, significant improvements in what was previously considered an irreversible condition. This shift from managing decline to supporting regeneration is profound. Ongoing research at institutions like Dalhousie University, alongside pharmaceutical development of compounds like CKBR-12, continues to validate ibogaine's potential. Provisional patents are even being filed for methods that provide rapid symptom reduction in neurodegenerative disorders. For millions affected by Parkinson's, ibogaine offers not just symptom management, but genuine hope for a better quality of life.]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">TheGDNFConnectionHowIbogaineTriggersBrainRepairinParkinsonsDisease</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:27:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <enclosure
        url="https://oimqzyfmglyhljjuboek.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/IBoga_Podcast_Files/TheGDNFConnectionHowIbogaineTriggersBrainRepairinParkinsonsDisease.mp3"
        length="12345678"
        type="audio/mpeg" />
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
    </item>


  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The Pain Reset: Research on Ibogaine's Unprecedented Relief for Chronic Neuropathic Pain]]></title>
      <itunes:image href="https://oimqzyfmglyhljjuboek.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/IBoga_Podcast_Files/ThePainResetResearchonIbogainesUnprecedentedReliefforChronicNeuropathicPain_Episode_Image.jpeg" />
      <description><![CDATA[A recent case report in *Frontiers in Pain Research* documented the extraordinary story of a 53-year-old client suffering from severe neuropathic pain for twenty years after a brachial plexus nerve root avulsion. He had exhausted every conventional treatment, yet after ibogaine therapy, he achieved a 100% reduction in his quantitative pain scores, essentially eliminating the pain that had defined his life for decades.

That research represents profound hope for millions living with intractable chronic pain. Today, we're going to dive into the unique science behind this breakthrough and learn about clients like Mark who are finding relief. Mark’s story began with a devastating motorcycle accident that left him with unrelenting nerve pain. After two decades of struggle, he had exhausted every medical option—from pharmaceuticals to surgeries—and was facing a last resort: a highly invasive procedure to burn the nerves in his spine. Then, he discovered ibogaine.

Let's hear his story.

Mark, a 53-year-old man, endured unimaginable suffering for two decades. His brachial plexus nerve root avulsion, a severe injury where nerves are torn from the spinal cord, plunged him into a world of constant burning, shooting, and electric pain. This wasn't just physical discomfort; it was a daily torture that eroded his quality of life. His struggle exemplifies the profound challenge of neuropathic pain, which isn't caused by tissue injury but by damage to the nerves themselves. These malfunctioning nerves send persistent, often debilitating, pain signals, long after any initial injury has healed.

Conditions like diabetic neuropathy, phantom limb pain, trigeminal neuralgia, and complex regional pain syndrome all fall under this umbrella. Traditional treatments often provide limited relief. Opioids are frequently ineffective for nerve pain, and while gabapentin or pregabalin can help, they often come with cognitive dulling and only modest benefits. Antidepressants take weeks to work and carry their own list of side effects. For Mark, and countless others, these options simply weren't enough. He had tried everything: gabapentin, tramadol, oxycontin, methadone, various antidepressants, mirror therapy, mindfulness, cranial sacral therapy, and even fetal stem cell therapy. Nothing provided sustainable relief. The pain was relentless, forcing him to consider a DREZ surgery, a procedure that would essentially burn the nerves in his spinal cord, as a final, desperate attempt.

Ibogaine works on neuropathic pain through a unique, triple-mechanism approach, which is why it can address pain that conventional medicine cannot touch. First, it acts as an NMDA receptor antagonist. These NMDA receptors are central to what we call "wind-up" pain, where pain signals amplify over time, making the nervous system increasingly sensitive. By blocking these receptors, similar to how ketamine works, ibogaine interrupts this amplification cycle, effectively hitting the reset button on chronic pain signaling. This is crucial for conditions where the nervous system has become hypersensitized.

Second, ibogaine has a special affinity for sigma-2 receptors. Research suggests that compounds acting on these sigma receptors can modulate pain perception at both the spinal and supraspinal levels. This means ibogaine isn't just masking pain; it's influencing how your brain and spinal cord process pain signals, offering a deeper level of relief.

But perhaps the most revolutionary aspect is ibogaine's third mechanism: neurotrophic factor stimulation. Ibogaine stimulates the production of Glial Cell Line-Derived Neurotrophic Factor, or GDNF. GDNF is a protein that has been shown to prevent and even reverse sensory abnormalities in models of neuropathic pain. This means ibogaine isn't just managing symptoms; it's promoting actual nerve repair and regeneration. This ability to address the underlying nerve damage sets it apart from nearly every other pain treatment available today.

For Mark, the transformation was profound. During his ibogaine treatment, which involved both flood dose and saturation protocols, he described the experience not as pain, but as an "unraveling of chaos." The sensation of his chronic pain simply wasn't there. This immediate shift was followed by sustained relief. Quantitative pain scores, measured using the DN4 scale, showed a 100% reduction in his neuropathic pain. These improvements were sustained throughout four treatment phases, with outpatient maintenance using small, daily doses of ibogaine, ranging from 40 to 250 milligrams. This regimen provided him with long-term relief for a condition previously deemed intractable.

Mark's case is particularly significant because nerve root avulsion pain is one of the most severe and difficult-to-treat conditions known. If ibogaine can eliminate pain in such an extreme case, its implications for other chronic, severe neuropathic pain conditions are truly profound. This groundbreaking outcome offers a new possibility for those facing similar desperate situations, like the DREZ surgery Mark was contemplating.

Beyond the full psychoactive experience of a flood dose, research is also exploring novel, non-hallucinogenic iboga derivatives, sometimes called ibogalogs. Compounds like Tabernanthalog, or TBG, are showing incredible promise. In animal studies, these derivatives have been found to significantly decrease mechanical hyperalgesia and allodynia, which are heightened sensitivities to pain and touch. They also mitigate inflammatory markers like Substance P and CGRP, reduce pro-inflammatory cytokines, and even improve restricted locomotor activity while offering anxiolytic effects. The exciting potential here is the possibility of pain relief without the intense psychoactive effects of a full ibogaine dose, offering a gentler option for chronic pain clients in the future.

The clinical applications of ibogaine and its derivatives for pain extend beyond rare conditions like Mark's. While specific research on fibromyalgia is limited, the mechanisms of ibogaine suggest significant potential. The widespread pain, fatigue, and cognitive difficulties characteristic of fibromyalgia could benefit from ibogaine’s neurotrophic factors, NMDA antagonism, and anti-inflammatory effects, all of which address pathways implicated in the condition. Anecdotal reports from clients already hint at significant relief.

For clients suffering from both chronic pain and opioid dependence, ibogaine offers a unique dual benefit. It can lower opioid tolerance, allowing for a reduction or even cessation of opioid use while simultaneously improving pain control. By restoring natural opioid signaling through its sigma-2 receptor affinity, ibogaine addresses both the dependence and the underlying pain in one comprehensive treatment. We’ve seen clients successfully manage their hydromorphone, oxycodone, and morphine dependence using ibogaine microdosing protocols while maintaining improved pain levels.

It's important to understand that pain management with ibogaine may require different protocols than addiction treatment. Often, it involves a combination of flood doses followed by extended microdosing, or saturation protocols to maintain consistent noribogaine levels in the system. Doses can be flexible, from 20 to 250 milligrams daily, adjusted to the client's pain severity. This is not meant to be a forever treatment, but rather an ongoing support during a critical healing window, allowing the brain to rewire and repair.

At Iboga Wellness Institute, all our protocols are medically supervised. We conduct comprehensive screenings, and clients receive 24/7 cardiac monitoring throughout their treatment. Co-administering magnesium, for example, is one of our many safety measures designed to protect the heart and ensure a powerful compound becomes breakthrough medicine.

Ibogaine represents a profound paradigm shift, addressing pain not just at the surface level, but at the neurological roots, repairing brain circuits conventional medicine cannot. For those who have tried everything else, exhausted all options, and are facing invasive surgeries or indefinite opioid dependence, ibogaine offers a unique, evidence-based pathway. It brings the hope that the intractable cycle of pain might finally be broken, ushering in a new possibility for healing.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[A recent case report in *Frontiers in Pain Research* documented the extraordinary story of a 53-year-old client suffering from severe neuropathic pain for twenty years after a brachial plexus nerve root avulsion. He had exhausted every conventional treatment, yet after ibogaine therapy, he achieved a 100% reduction in his quantitative pain scores, essentially eliminating the pain that had defined his life for decades.

That research represents profound hope for millions living with intractable chronic pain. Today, we're going to dive into the unique science behind this breakthrough and learn about clients like Mark who are finding relief. Mark’s story began with a devastating motorcycle accident that left him with unrelenting nerve pain. After two decades of struggle, he had exhausted every medical option—from pharmaceuticals to surgeries—and was facing a last resort: a highly invasive procedure to burn the nerves in his spine. Then, he discovered ibogaine.

Let's hear his story.

Mark, a 53-year-old man, endured unimaginable suffering for two decades. His brachial plexus nerve root avulsion, a severe injury where nerves are torn from the spinal cord, plunged him into a world of constant burning, shooting, and electric pain. This wasn't just physical discomfort; it was a daily torture that eroded his quality of life. His struggle exemplifies the profound challenge of neuropathic pain, which isn't caused by tissue injury but by damage to the nerves themselves. These malfunctioning nerves send persistent, often debilitating, pain signals, long after any initial injury has healed.

Conditions like diabetic neuropathy, phantom limb pain, trigeminal neuralgia, and complex regional pain syndrome all fall under this umbrella. Traditional treatments often provide limited relief. Opioids are frequently ineffective for nerve pain, and while gabapentin or pregabalin can help, they often come with cognitive dulling and only modest benefits. Antidepressants take weeks to work and carry their own list of side effects. For Mark, and countless others, these options simply weren't enough. He had tried everything: gabapentin, tramadol, oxycontin, methadone, various antidepressants, mirror therapy, mindfulness, cranial sacral therapy, and even fetal stem cell therapy. Nothing provided sustainable relief. The pain was relentless, forcing him to consider a DREZ surgery, a procedure that would essentially burn the nerves in his spinal cord, as a final, desperate attempt.

Ibogaine works on neuropathic pain through a unique, triple-mechanism approach, which is why it can address pain that conventional medicine cannot touch. First, it acts as an NMDA receptor antagonist. These NMDA receptors are central to what we call "wind-up" pain, where pain signals amplify over time, making the nervous system increasingly sensitive. By blocking these receptors, similar to how ketamine works, ibogaine interrupts this amplification cycle, effectively hitting the reset button on chronic pain signaling. This is crucial for conditions where the nervous system has become hypersensitized.

Second, ibogaine has a special affinity for sigma-2 receptors. Research suggests that compounds acting on these sigma receptors can modulate pain perception at both the spinal and supraspinal levels. This means ibogaine isn't just masking pain; it's influencing how your brain and spinal cord process pain signals, offering a deeper level of relief.

But perhaps the most revolutionary aspect is ibogaine's third mechanism: neurotrophic factor stimulation. Ibogaine stimulates the production of Glial Cell Line-Derived Neurotrophic Factor, or GDNF. GDNF is a protein that has been shown to prevent and even reverse sensory abnormalities in models of neuropathic pain. This means ibogaine isn't just managing symptoms; it's promoting actual nerve repair and regeneration. This ability to address the underlying nerve damage sets it apart from nearly every other pain treatment available today.

For Mark, the transformation was profound. During his ibogaine treatment, which involved both flood dose and saturation protocols, he described the experience not as pain, but as an "unraveling of chaos." The sensation of his chronic pain simply wasn't there. This immediate shift was followed by sustained relief. Quantitative pain scores, measured using the DN4 scale, showed a 100% reduction in his neuropathic pain. These improvements were sustained throughout four treatment phases, with outpatient maintenance using small, daily doses of ibogaine, ranging from 40 to 250 milligrams. This regimen provided him with long-term relief for a condition previously deemed intractable.

Mark's case is particularly significant because nerve root avulsion pain is one of the most severe and difficult-to-treat conditions known. If ibogaine can eliminate pain in such an extreme case, its implications for other chronic, severe neuropathic pain conditions are truly profound. This groundbreaking outcome offers a new possibility for those facing similar desperate situations, like the DREZ surgery Mark was contemplating.

Beyond the full psychoactive experience of a flood dose, research is also exploring novel, non-hallucinogenic iboga derivatives, sometimes called ibogalogs. Compounds like Tabernanthalog, or TBG, are showing incredible promise. In animal studies, these derivatives have been found to significantly decrease mechanical hyperalgesia and allodynia, which are heightened sensitivities to pain and touch. They also mitigate inflammatory markers like Substance P and CGRP, reduce pro-inflammatory cytokines, and even improve restricted locomotor activity while offering anxiolytic effects. The exciting potential here is the possibility of pain relief without the intense psychoactive effects of a full ibogaine dose, offering a gentler option for chronic pain clients in the future.

The clinical applications of ibogaine and its derivatives for pain extend beyond rare conditions like Mark's. While specific research on fibromyalgia is limited, the mechanisms of ibogaine suggest significant potential. The widespread pain, fatigue, and cognitive difficulties characteristic of fibromyalgia could benefit from ibogaine’s neurotrophic factors, NMDA antagonism, and anti-inflammatory effects, all of which address pathways implicated in the condition. Anecdotal reports from clients already hint at significant relief.

For clients suffering from both chronic pain and opioid dependence, ibogaine offers a unique dual benefit. It can lower opioid tolerance, allowing for a reduction or even cessation of opioid use while simultaneously improving pain control. By restoring natural opioid signaling through its sigma-2 receptor affinity, ibogaine addresses both the dependence and the underlying pain in one comprehensive treatment. We’ve seen clients successfully manage their hydromorphone, oxycodone, and morphine dependence using ibogaine microdosing protocols while maintaining improved pain levels.

It's important to understand that pain management with ibogaine may require different protocols than addiction treatment. Often, it involves a combination of flood doses followed by extended microdosing, or saturation protocols to maintain consistent noribogaine levels in the system. Doses can be flexible, from 20 to 250 milligrams daily, adjusted to the client's pain severity. This is not meant to be a forever treatment, but rather an ongoing support during a critical healing window, allowing the brain to rewire and repair.

At Iboga Wellness Institute, all our protocols are medically supervised. We conduct comprehensive screenings, and clients receive 24/7 cardiac monitoring throughout their treatment. Co-administering magnesium, for example, is one of our many safety measures designed to protect the heart and ensure a powerful compound becomes breakthrough medicine.

Ibogaine represents a profound paradigm shift, addressing pain not just at the surface level, but at the neurological roots, repairing brain circuits conventional medicine cannot. For those who have tried everything else, exhausted all options, and are facing invasive surgeries or indefinite opioid dependence, ibogaine offers a unique, evidence-based pathway. It brings the hope that the intractable cycle of pain might finally be broken, ushering in a new possibility for healing.]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ThePainResetResearchonIbogainesUnprecedentedReliefforChronicNeuropathicPain</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 09:55:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <enclosure
        url="https://oimqzyfmglyhljjuboek.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/IBoga_Podcast_Files/ThePainResetResearchonIbogainesUnprecedentedReliefforChronicNeuropathicPain.mp3"
        length="12345678"
        type="audio/mpeg" />
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>