<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">

  <channel>
    <title>REWIRED: THE IBOGAINE EXPERIENCE</title>
    <link>https://theibogainstitute.org</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <description>Rewired: The Ibogaine Experience shares real stories from patients and families who have experienced ibogaine therapy for PTSD, addiction, Parkinson's disease, and other conditions.
    
Brought to you by IBOGA Wellness Institute.
    
Every week, you'll hear honest conversations about struggle, recovery, and what happens after treatment. Veterans with PTSD, people overcoming addiction, patients with Parkinson's experiencing symptom improvements, and the family members who supported them through the decision.
    
These are authentic stories backed by research. No false promises. No wellness industry marketing. Just real people sharing what worked when traditional treatments failed.
    
If you're researching options for someone you love, or seeking answers for yourself, you're not alone.
    
New episodes every week. Real stories. Real outcomes. Real hope.</description>

    <!-- Set this to the final public URL where THIS RSS XML is hosted -->
    <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aidatamanagement/Iboga_Podcast/main/Rewired.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

    <!-- Recommended metadata -->
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:15:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>

    <!-- Spotify reads iTunes podcast tags -->
    <itunes:author>Sarah Mitchell</itunes:author>
    <itunes:summary>Sarah Mitchell has personal experience researching treatments for a loved one at 2am. She knows what it's like to be exhausted, hopeful, and trying to separate science from marketing. After seeing the real results ibogaine offers, Sarah brings you the research and shares authentic experiences from people who have walked this path.
Sarah speaks to you as a peer, not an expert. She's been where you are.</itunes:summary>
    <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>

    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:name>Shubakar Poda</itunes:name>
      <itunes:email>contactus@theibogainstitute.org</itunes:email>
    </itunes:owner>

    <itunes:category text="Technology"/>

    <!-- Prefer hosting your own cover art long-term, but this URL is syntactically fine -->
    <itunes:image href="https://oimqzyfmglyhljjuboek.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/IBoga_Podcast_Files/Rewired%20by%20Iboga%20Wellness%20Institute%20Main%20banner.jpg"/>

    <!-- Optional nice-to-haves -->
    <itunes:subtitle>Supabase-hosted podcast feed test</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:keywords>supabase, podcast, testing, aidm</itunes:keywords>



  
 
    

  
  
    
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[One Session, Lasting Freedom—The Long-Term Effects of Ibogaine]]></title>
      <itunes:image href="https://oimqzyfmglyhljjuboek.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/IBoga_Podcast_Files/OneSessionLastingFreedomTheLongTermEffectsofIbogaine_Episode_Image.jpeg" />
      <description><![CDATA[A twelve-month study revealed that fifty percent of opioid-dependent clients remained completely abstinent one year after ibogaine treatment. That success rate is five times higher than traditional rehab programs. Another compelling outcome is an 88% reduction in PTSD symptoms sustained at six months, showcasing ibogaine's wide-ranging impact beyond just addiction.

This research represents hope for millions seeking a lasting change. Today, you'll hear about Marcus, a client who found profound freedom after years battling an insidious addiction.

Let's hear their story.

Marcus, a 42-year-old veteran and dedicated construction worker, was once defined by his opioid addiction. It had started innocently enough, a prescription for a back injury, but it quickly escalated, gripping him for over a decade. He was a father of two, but his children knew a version of him clouded by constant cravings, irritability, and the ever-present fear of withdrawal. His life became an exhausting cycle of securing his next dose, losing jobs, and alienating those he loved most. The man he once was felt lost beneath the weight of his struggle.

He had tried everything. Multiple 30-day rehab programs offered temporary breaks, but the insidious neurological wiring of addiction always pulled him back. Suboxone helped manage the physical symptoms but often felt like substituting one dependency for another. Therapy provided tools, but without addressing the underlying brain chemistry, the cravings and the psychological pull were too strong. Every attempt left him more defeated, reinforcing the belief that true, lasting freedom was an impossible dream. The sheer terror of withdrawal was a cage he couldn't escape, always drawing him back to the very substance that was destroying his life.

Desperate and at his lowest point, Marcus stumbled upon information about ibogaine. He was skeptical; how could a single session possibly undo a decade of addiction? But the testimonials of a neurological reset, of withdrawal being virtually eliminated, captivated him. He meticulously researched the Iboga Wellness Institute, drawn in by their comprehensive safety protocols and the promise of a complete re-wiring rather than mere symptom management. The blend of ancient wisdom and modern neuroscience spoke to something deep within him, urging him to take a chance.

His journey to treatment began with a rigorous medical screening. At the Institute, he was under constant 24/7 medical supervision, including continuous cardiac monitoring and magnesium co-administration, a vital part of our safety protocols. The treatment itself was intense, an introspective journey that felt like a lifetime's worth of therapy condensed into a few hours. Marcus described experiencing a profound "life review," confronting past traumas and gaining incredible clarity. The physical withdrawal symptoms he dreaded so much, the ones that had always broken his resolve, simply dissipated, almost miraculously, within 24 hours. He lay there, expecting the torment, but it never came.

When he emerged from the deep state, Marcus felt an immediate, profound shift. His mind was clear, unburdened by the constant noise of cravings and the shadow of withdrawal. It was as if his brain had been physically reset to a pre-addiction state. This wasn't just abstinence; it was neurological transformation. Over the following weeks, his energy returned, his focus sharpened, and he began to engage with the world, and more importantly, with his family, in a way he hadn't in years. His wife remarked that he was truly "present" for the first time she could remember. He found himself thinking clearly, feeling emotions without the dulling effect of opioids, and experiencing a profound sense of peace. The GDNF production stimulated by ibogaine was actively repairing the damaged dopamine circuits in his brain, bringing about a healing conventional medicine simply couldn't achieve. This was indeed "where broken becomes breakthrough."

Now, six months post-treatment, Marcus's life is a testament to the lasting freedom ibogaine can offer. He remains completely abstinent, the cravings a distant memory. He’s back at work, performing at his peak, and most importantly, he’s an engaged and loving father again. The long-term improvements extend beyond just sobriety; his family relationships have been significantly mended, a testament to the comprehensive healing that takes place. He continues with regular integration therapy, reinforcing the insights gained during his ibogaine experience. The calm in his eyes, the renewed purpose in his stride, and the genuine laughter with his children are all proof of the powerful, enduring impact of one session. His story truly embodies what it means to achieve lasting freedom.

Learn more: https://theibogainstitute.org]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[A twelve-month study revealed that fifty percent of opioid-dependent clients remained completely abstinent one year after ibogaine treatment. That success rate is five times higher than traditional rehab programs. Another compelling outcome is an 88% reduction in PTSD symptoms sustained at six months, showcasing ibogaine's wide-ranging impact beyond just addiction.

This research represents hope for millions seeking a lasting change. Today, you'll hear about Marcus, a client who found profound freedom after years battling an insidious addiction.

Let's hear their story.

Marcus, a 42-year-old veteran and dedicated construction worker, was once defined by his opioid addiction. It had started innocently enough, a prescription for a back injury, but it quickly escalated, gripping him for over a decade. He was a father of two, but his children knew a version of him clouded by constant cravings, irritability, and the ever-present fear of withdrawal. His life became an exhausting cycle of securing his next dose, losing jobs, and alienating those he loved most. The man he once was felt lost beneath the weight of his struggle.

He had tried everything. Multiple 30-day rehab programs offered temporary breaks, but the insidious neurological wiring of addiction always pulled him back. Suboxone helped manage the physical symptoms but often felt like substituting one dependency for another. Therapy provided tools, but without addressing the underlying brain chemistry, the cravings and the psychological pull were too strong. Every attempt left him more defeated, reinforcing the belief that true, lasting freedom was an impossible dream. The sheer terror of withdrawal was a cage he couldn't escape, always drawing him back to the very substance that was destroying his life.

Desperate and at his lowest point, Marcus stumbled upon information about ibogaine. He was skeptical; how could a single session possibly undo a decade of addiction? But the testimonials of a neurological reset, of withdrawal being virtually eliminated, captivated him. He meticulously researched the Iboga Wellness Institute, drawn in by their comprehensive safety protocols and the promise of a complete re-wiring rather than mere symptom management. The blend of ancient wisdom and modern neuroscience spoke to something deep within him, urging him to take a chance.

His journey to treatment began with a rigorous medical screening. At the Institute, he was under constant 24/7 medical supervision, including continuous cardiac monitoring and magnesium co-administration, a vital part of our safety protocols. The treatment itself was intense, an introspective journey that felt like a lifetime's worth of therapy condensed into a few hours. Marcus described experiencing a profound "life review," confronting past traumas and gaining incredible clarity. The physical withdrawal symptoms he dreaded so much, the ones that had always broken his resolve, simply dissipated, almost miraculously, within 24 hours. He lay there, expecting the torment, but it never came.

When he emerged from the deep state, Marcus felt an immediate, profound shift. His mind was clear, unburdened by the constant noise of cravings and the shadow of withdrawal. It was as if his brain had been physically reset to a pre-addiction state. This wasn't just abstinence; it was neurological transformation. Over the following weeks, his energy returned, his focus sharpened, and he began to engage with the world, and more importantly, with his family, in a way he hadn't in years. His wife remarked that he was truly "present" for the first time she could remember. He found himself thinking clearly, feeling emotions without the dulling effect of opioids, and experiencing a profound sense of peace. The GDNF production stimulated by ibogaine was actively repairing the damaged dopamine circuits in his brain, bringing about a healing conventional medicine simply couldn't achieve. This was indeed "where broken becomes breakthrough."

Now, six months post-treatment, Marcus's life is a testament to the lasting freedom ibogaine can offer. He remains completely abstinent, the cravings a distant memory. He’s back at work, performing at his peak, and most importantly, he’s an engaged and loving father again. The long-term improvements extend beyond just sobriety; his family relationships have been significantly mended, a testament to the comprehensive healing that takes place. He continues with regular integration therapy, reinforcing the insights gained during his ibogaine experience. The calm in his eyes, the renewed purpose in his stride, and the genuine laughter with his children are all proof of the powerful, enduring impact of one session. His story truly embodies what it means to achieve lasting freedom.

Learn more: https://theibogainstitute.org]]></content:encoded>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">OneSessionLastingFreedomTheLongTermEffectsofIbogaine</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:36:53 GMT</pubDate>
      <enclosure
        url="https://oimqzyfmglyhljjuboek.supabase.co/storage/v1/object/public/IBoga_Podcast_Files/OneSessionLastingFreedomTheLongTermEffectsofIbogaine.mp3"
        length="12345678"
        type="audio/mpeg" />
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
